<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>rv4102</title>
    <link>https://rv4102.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on rv4102</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.5</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 12:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rv4102.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My CDC Internship Drive Experience</title>
      <link>https://rv4102.github.io/posts/cdc_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rv4102.github.io/posts/cdc_experience/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! This is a personal blog about my journey towards securing an internship at Sprinklr for the summer of 2024 through IIT Kharagpur&amp;rsquo;s CDC Internship process.
. . .
The Beginning Owing to Covid, our batch had to wait 2 months for college to begin and even when it did during December 2020, it was online! What a bummer for a starry-eyed fresher. Among the hubbub regarding various societies and their selections, I came across Business Club and was competent enough to clear their selection process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First</title>
      <link>https://rv4102.github.io/posts/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 15:55:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rv4102.github.io/posts/first/</guid>
      <description>Hello there! 👋🏻 This is the start of my blog/ personal website!
Here is my playlist (so you can know me better): </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Interests!</title>
      <link>https://rv4102.github.io/interests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rv4102.github.io/interests/</guid>
      <description>Some of the stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on / am interested in CSE Freshers&amp;rsquo; Nite Went out of my way to perform a Mad-Lib theatre with my friend Shivam Raj Sketches I&amp;rsquo;ve made Check out more of them here</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://rv4102.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rv4102.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>My Projects (Group and Personal): Distributed Database Development | Distributed Systems Objective: Create a replicated database with sharding and incorporate Write-Ahead Logging mechanism Created a dockerized database container with consistent hashing for load-balancing, ensuring balanced distribution of write requests among shard replicas. Ensured scalability by supporting faster reads with dynamic increment of replicas and larger database size with additional shards and servers. Developed a Write-Ahead Logging (WAL) mechanism for data consistency and recovery by first recording changes before committing them to disk.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
